Ke Qian alex

Rogers ARke@mnch.xyz678 660 8988gh/xenialaq

Work Experience

Walmart GeC, Global Integrated Fulfillment

Software Engineer III (Automation)

2018.06 - Present AR

Developed a comprehensive automation solution based on Node.js and Appium and enabled automation on GIF products. The data-driven solution efficiently handles hundreds of test orders per minute. A series of JavaScript kits streamline the access of microservices and allow full lifecycle control of orders. Reduced running time by managing orders, devices and API accesses through pipelines and parallelization.

Continuously improve and add features such as reusable test vehicle, test data DSL, async, CI/CD, cloud testing, performance recording, advanced reporting and BDD support. Learn from other Walmart teams and third-party solutions to reduce development cost. Enabled in-house alternative to minimize interruption upon issue with a key SaaS provider, and repurposed the SaaS solution as a candidate for BYOD testing.

Work with developers to improve testability and reliability. Onboard testers to automation. Finalize test plans & scopes within the cross-functional team. Provide guidance on test case writing and scripting. Support continuous learning and collaboration by allocating works, sharing demos, enforcing coding standards e.g. ESLint & Git workflow.

Cornell University, Language Resource Center

Developer 2017.06 - 2018.05 NY

Built and maintained WALAT (WAL Authoring Tool), a courseware creator for Web Audio Lab, an online learning platform.

Before, rich media courses required Web development skills and manual compilation of texts, scripts and media. Usually Center staff acted as authors due to high demand from intstructors.

WALAT was written in Angular to streamline the courseware creation process with sets of forms, page templates, drag-and-drop command editor and an asset manager for embedding media files. A desktop version was made with Node, SQLite and Electron without costing extra server resources.

WalmartLabs

Tools and Automation Intern 2016.06 - 2016.08 CA

Developed SRT, a full-stack Java project visualizing test results.

SRT retrieves data from TestRail API and Jenkins DB, aggregates and stores them using Hibernate, and exposes RESTful endpoints with which the dashboard can visualize automation & test stats and drill down using filters. Optimized chart loading time by caching SQL query results. Created an admin UI to manage configs and scheduled tasks.

Sam's is still using SRT for test reporting and SRT was adapted for GIF backend E2E testing.

Education

Cornell University

Master's - Information Science - GPA: 3.26

2017.08 - 2018.05 NY

Project Microsoft Azure · A browser-based cluster configurator for Azure Service Fabric on-prem users Led a team of 3 and worked closely with the client to visualize cluster hierarchy with D3.js and Matter.js the physics engine. Support for drag-drop, WYSIWYG, two-way conversion between designer and JSON editor, and JSON Schema validation to notify users of missing or incorrect fields.

Cornell University

Bachelor's - Computer Science, Information Science - GPA: 3.12

2013.08 - 2017.05 NY

Honors Fall 2014 Dean's List

MATLAB Consultant 2016.08 - 2017.05

Student Assembly Tech Committee Developer 2015.10 - 2016.06

Highlights

Five years of Web development experience and two years of mobile testing experience. Proficient in JavaScript (Node.js), ES6+ features and common frameworks (Express, RN).

Working knowledge of Java development. Full stack project experience with Grails and Spring frameworks. Experience with Linux environment (Shell), CI/CD, microservices, SQL, NoSQL, RESTful, WebSocket, MQ technologies. Familiar with algorithms and data structures, past experiences with DBMS, operating systems, data analysis (Python). Able to utilize PaaS & SaaS solutions and forge partnership with service providers. Excellent English proficiency.

Languages Mandarin Chinese, English